<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<component type="desktop">
  <id>org.kde.kexi-3.2</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>LGPL-2.0+</project_license>
  <name>Kexi</name>
  <name xml:lang="ast">Kexi</name>
  <name xml:lang="bs">Kexi</name>
  <name xml:lang="ca">Kexi</name>
  <name xml:lang="ca-valencia">Kexi</name>
  <name xml:lang="cs">Kexi</name>
  <name xml:lang="da">Kexi</name>
  <name xml:lang="de">Kexi</name>
  <name xml:lang="el">Kexi</name>
  <name xml:lang="en-GB">Kexi</name>
  <name xml:lang="es">Kexi</name>
  <name xml:lang="et">Kexi</name>
  <name xml:lang="fi">Kexi</name>
  <name xml:lang="fr">Kexi</name>
  <name xml:lang="gl">Kexi</name>
  <name xml:lang="ia">Kexi</name>
  <name xml:lang="id">Kexi</name>
  <name xml:lang="it">Kexi</name>
  <name xml:lang="ja">Kexi</name>
  <name xml:lang="ka">Kexi</name>
  <name xml:lang="ko">Kexi</name>
  <name xml:lang="nb">Kexi</name>
  <name xml:lang="nl">Kexi</name>
  <name xml:lang="pl">Kexi</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt">Kexi</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt-BR">Kexi</name>
  <name xml:lang="ru">Kexi</name>
  <name xml:lang="sk">Kexi</name>
  <name xml:lang="sl">Kexi</name>
  <name xml:lang="sv">Kexi</name>
  <name xml:lang="uk">Kexi</name>
  <name xml:lang="x-test">xxKexixx</name>
  <name xml:lang="zh-CN">Kexi</name>
  <summary>Visual database apps builder</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ca">Constructor visual d'aplicacions de bases de dades</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ca-valencia">Constructor visual d'aplicacions de bases de dades</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="de">Visuelle Erstellung von Datenbankanwendungen</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="el">Πρόγραμμα κατασκευής εφαρμογών με οπτική βάση δεδομένων</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="en-GB">Visual database apps builder</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="es">Constructor visual de aplicaciones de base de datos</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="et">Visuaalne andmebaasirakenduste looja</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fi">Visuaalinen tietokantasovellusten luonti</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fr">Constructeur d'applications de bases de données visuel</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="gl">Construtor visual de aplicativos de base de datos</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ia">Constructor visual de apps per base de datos</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="id">Pembangun apps database visual</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="it">Generatore visuale di applicazioni di banche dati</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ko">비주얼 데이터베이스 앱 빌더</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nl">Visuele database van bouwer van apps</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pl">Tworzenie wizualnych aplikacji baz danych</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt">Construtor visual de aplicações de bases de dados</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt-BR">Construtor visual de aplicativos de banco de dados</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="ru">Среда для создания приложений, работающих с базами данных</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sk">Vizuálny tvorca databázových aplikácií</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sl">Izdelovalec vizualnih aplikacij za baze podatkov</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sv">Visuellt byggverktyg för databasprogram</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="tr">Görsel veritabanı uygulamaları yapıcısı</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="uk">Програма для побудови візуальних обробників баз даних</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="x-test">xxVisual database apps builderxx</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="zh-CN">可视化数据库应用程序构建工具</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      Kexi is a visual database applications builder. It can be used for designing database applications,
      inserting and editing data, performing queries, and processing data. Forms can be created
      to provide a custom interface to your data. All database objects - tables, queries, forms,
      reports, etc. - are stored in the database, making it easy to share data and design.
    </p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">El Kexi és un constructor visual de base de dades. Es pot utilitzar per dissenyar aplicacions de bases de dades, inserció i edició de dades, execució de consultes, i procés de dades. Es poden generar formularis per proporcionar una interfície personalitzada a les dades. Tots els objectes de les bases de dades -taules, consultes, formularis, informes, etc.- s'emmagatzemen en la base de dades, facilitant compartir les dades i el disseny.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Kexi és un constructor visual de base de dades. Es pot utilitzar per dissenyar aplicacions de bases de dades, inserció i edició de dades, execució de consultes, i procés de dades. Es poden generar formularis per proporcionar una interfície personalitzada a les dades. Tots els objectes de les bases de dades -taules, consultes, formularis, informes, etc.- s'emmagatzemen en la base de dades, facilitant compartir les dades i el disseny.</p>
    <p xml:lang="de">Kexi ist ein visueller Generator für Datenbankanwendungen. Es kann für den Entwurf von Datenbankanwendungen, zum Einfügen und Bearbeiten von Daten, zur Durchführung von Abfragen und zur Verarbeitung von Daten verwendet werden. Formulare können erstellt werden, um eine eigene Schnittstelle zu Ihren Daten bereitzustellen. Alle Datenbankobjekte - Tabellen, Abfragen, Formulare, Berichte usw. - werden in der Datenbank gespeichert, was die gemeinsame Nutzung von Daten und Entwurf erleichtert.</p>
    <p xml:lang="el">Το Kexi είναι ένα πρόγραμμα κατασκευής εφαρμογών με οπτική βάση δεδομένων. Χρησιμεύει για τη σχεδίαση εφαρμογών βάσεων δεδομένων, την εισαγωγή και διόρθωση δεδομένων, την εκτέλεση ερωτήσεων και την επεξεργασία δεδομένων. Οι φόρμες κατασκευάζονται για να παρέχουν ένα προσαρμοσμένο περιβάλλον χρήσης για τα δεδομένα σας. Όλα τα αντικείμενα της βάσης - πίνακες, ερωτήσεις, φόρμες, αναφορές, κλπ. - αποθηκεύονται στη βάση δεδομένων, διευκολύνοντας το διαμοιρασμό δεδομένων και σχεδίασης.</p>
    <p xml:lang="en-GB">Kexi is a visual database applications builder. It can be used for designing database applications, inserting and editing data, performing queries, and processing data. Forms can be created to provide a custom interface to your data. All database objects - tables, queries, forms, reports, etc. - are stored in the database, making it easy to share data and design.</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">Kexi es un creador visual de aplicaciones de bases de datos. Se puede usar para diseñar aplicaciones de bases de datos, insertar y editar datos, realizar consultas y procesar datos. Se pueden crear formularios para proporcionar una interfaz personalizada para sus datos. Todos los objetos de la base de datos (tablas, consultas, formularios, informes, etc.) se almacenan en la base de datos, facilitando el intercambio de datos y diseños.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fi">Kexi on ohjelma tietokantasovellusten luomiseen visuaalisesti. Se on osa Calligra-ohjelmistoa. Sen avulla voi suunnitella tietokantasovelluksia, lisätä ja muokata tietoja, suorittaa kyselyjä ja käsitellä tietoja. Voit luoda lomakkeita mukauttaaksesi tietojesi käyttöliittymää. Kaikki tietokantaoliot – taulukot, kyselyt, lomakkeet, raportit jne. – tallennetaan tietokantaan, joten tiedon jako ja suunnittelu on helppoa.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fr">Kexi est un constructeur d'applications de bases de données visuel. Il peut être utilisé pour concevoir des applications de base de données, insérer et éditer des données, effectuer des requêtes, et traiter des données. Des formulaires peuvent être créés pour fournir une interface personnalisée pour vos données. Tous les objets de bases de données (tables, requêtes, formulaires, rapports, etc.) sont stockés dans la base de données, simplifiant le partage de données et de design.</p>
    <p xml:lang="gl">Kexi é un construtor visual de aplicacións de base de datos. Pode usarse para deseñar aplicacións de base de datos, inserindo e editando datos, realizando consultas, e procesando datos. Poden crearse formularios para fornecer unha interface personalizada para os datos. Todos os obxectos de base de datos (táboas, consultas, formularios, informes, etc.) almacénanse na base de datos, facendo fácil compartir os datos e o deseño.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ia">Kexi es un constructor de applicationes de base de datos visual. Illo pote esser usate per designar applicationes de base de dato, insertar e modificar datos, executar queries, e processar datos. Formularios pote esser create per fornir un interfacie personalisate per tu datos. Omne objectos de datos - tabellas, queries, formularios, reportos, etc. - es immagazinate  in le base de datos, facente facile le compartir datos e designo.</p>
    <p xml:lang="id">Kexi adalah pembangun aplikasi database visual. Dapat digunakan untuk merancang aplikasi basis data, memasukkan dan mengedit data, melakukan queri, dan memproses data. Formulir dapat dibuat untuk memberikan antarmuka khusus ke data Anda. Semua objek basis data - tabel, queri, formulir, laporan, dll. - disimpan dalam basis data, sehingga mudah untuk berbagi data dan desain.</p>
    <p xml:lang="it">Kexi è uno strumento visuale per la creazione di banche dati. Può essere utilizzato per progettare applicazioni che usano banche dati, inserire e modificare dati, eseguire query ed elaborare dati. Puoi creare moduli per fornire un'interfaccia personalizzata ai tuoi dati. Tutti gli oggetti di una banca dati - tabelle, query, moduli, report - sono memorizzati nella banca dati stessa, semplificando la condivisione dei dati e la progettazione.</p>
    <p xml:lang="ko">Kexi는 시각적 데이터베이스 애플리케이션 빌더입니다. 데이터베이스 응용 프로그램 설계, 데이터 삽입 및 편집, 질의 수행 및 데이터 처리에 사용할 수 있습니다. 데이터에 사용자 정의 인터페이스를 제공하려면 양식을 생성할 수 있습니다. 모든 데이터베이스 개체(테이블, 질의, 양식, 보고서 등)가 데이터베이스에 저장되므로 데이터와 설계를 쉽게 공유할 수 있습니다.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">Kexi is een bouwer van toepassingen met een database op een visuele manier. Het kan gebruikt worden voor het ontwerpen van toepassingen met een database, gegevens invoeren en bewerken, zoekopdrachten uitvoeren en gegevens verwerken. Formulieren kunnen gemaakt worden om een aangepast interface naar uw gegevens te bieden. Alle database-objecten - tabellen, zoekopdrachten, formulieren, rapporten, etc. - worden opgeslagen in de database, waarmee het gemakkelijk wordt gegevens en ontwerp te delen.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pl">Kexi to aplikacja do wizualnego tworzenia bazdanych. Można jej używać do opracowywania programów bazodanowych,wstawiania, edycji i przetwarzania danych, a także do wykonywania zapytań.Dostęp do danych można zapewniać przy pomocy formularzy. Wszystkie obiekty bazy danych, tabele, zapytania, formularze i raporty, itp. są przechowywane w bazie danych, co czyni je łatwymi do współdzielenia i opracowywania.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">O Kexi é um criador de bases de dados visuais, que pode ser usado para desenhar aplicações de bases de dados, inserir e editar dados, executar pesquisas e processar os dados. Poderá criar formulários para oferecer uma interface personalizada para os seus dados. Todos os objectos da base de dados - tabelas, pesquisas, formulários, relatórios, etc. - são guardados na base de dados, tornando simples a partilha e o desenho dos dados.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Kexi é um construtor de aplicativos visuais de banco de dados. Pode ser usado para desenhar aplicativos de banco de dados, inserir e editar dados, executar pesquisas e processar dados. Podem ser criados formulários para oferecer uma interface personalizada para seus dados. Todos os objetos do banco de dados - tabelas, pesquisas, formulários, relatórios, etc. - são armazenados no próprio banco de dados, tornando simples o compartilhamento de dados e o visual.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sk">Kexi je vizuálny tvorca databáz, súčasť Calligra Suite. Dá sa použiť na návrh databázových aplikácií, vkladanie a úpravu údajov, vykonávanie dotazov a spracúvanie údajov. Formuláre sa dajú vytvoriť na poskytnutie vlastného rozhrania pre vaše údaje. Všetky databázové objekty - tabuľky, dotazy, formuláre, správy - sú uložené v databáze, čo uľahčuje zdieľanie dát a dizajn.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sl">Kexi je ustvarjalec vizualnih aplikacij za baze podatkov. Lahko se uporablja za oblikovanje aplikacije za baze podatkov, vstavljanje in urejanje podatkov, izvajanje poizvedb in obdelavo podatkov. Ustvarite lahko obrazce, da svojim podatkom omogočite vmesnik po meri. Vsi predmeti baze podatkov - tabele, poizvedbe, obrazci, poročila itd. - so shranjene v bazi podatkov, kar omogoča enostavno izmenjavo podatkov in oblikovanje.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">Kexi är ett visuell byggverktyg för databasprogram, en del av Calligra-sviten. Den kan användas för att skapa databasprogram, infoga och redigera data, ställa frågor och behandla data. Formulär kan skapas för att tillhandahålla ett anpassat gränssnitt för data. Alla databasobjekt (tabeller, frågor, formulär, rapporter, etc.) lagras i databasen, vilket gör det enkelt att dela data och konstruktion.</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">Kexi — програма для створення обробників баз даних у візуальному режимі. Цією програмою можна скористатися для створень мініпрограм для роботи з базами даних, додавання та редагування даних, виконання запитів та обробки даних. За допомогою створених програмою форм ви можете отримати потрібний вам режим доступу до ваших даних. Всі об’єкти баз даних — таблиці, запити, форми, звіти тощо, — зберігаються у самій базі даних, що спрощує поширення даних та представлення даних.</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxKexi is a visual database applications builder. It can be used for designing database applications, inserting and editing data, performing queries, and processing data. Forms can be created to provide a custom interface to your data. All database objects - tables, queries, forms, reports, etc. - are stored in the database, making it easy to share data and design.xx</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-CN">Kexi 是一款可视化的数据库应用程序构建工具。它可用于设计数据库应用程序、插入和编辑数据、执行查询、处理数据等。您可以创建表单作为数据的自定义接口。所有数据库对象——数据表、查询、表单、报告等——都存储在数据库中，方便数据共享和设计。</p>
    <p>Features:</p>
    <p xml:lang="bs">Osobine:</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca">Característiques:</p>
    <p xml:lang="ca-valencia">Característiques:</p>
    <p xml:lang="cs">Vlastnosti:</p>
    <p xml:lang="de">Funktionen:</p>
    <p xml:lang="el">Χαρακτηριστικά:</p>
    <p xml:lang="en-GB">Features:</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">Características:</p>
    <p xml:lang="et">Omadused:</p>
    <p xml:lang="fi">Ominaisuuksia:</p>
    <p xml:lang="fr">Fonctionnalités :</p>
    <p xml:lang="gl">Funcionalidades:</p>
    <p xml:lang="ia">Characteristicas</p>
    <p xml:lang="id">Fitur:</p>
    <p xml:lang="it">Funzionalità:</p>
    <p xml:lang="ja">機能:</p>
    <p xml:lang="ka">თვისებები:</p>
    <p xml:lang="ko">기능:</p>
    <p xml:lang="nb">Funksjoner:</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">Mogelijkheden:</p>
    <p xml:lang="pl">Możliwości:</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">Funcionalidades:</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Funcionalidades:</p>
    <p xml:lang="ru">Возможности:</p>
    <p xml:lang="sk">Funkcie:</p>
    <p xml:lang="sl">Zmožnosti:</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">Funktioner:</p>
    <p xml:lang="tr">Özellikler:</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">Можливості:</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxFeatures:xx</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-CN">程序功能：</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Full visual designers for tables, queries, forms and reports</li>
      <li xml:lang="bs">Potpuni vizualni dizajneri za tablice , upite , obrasce i izvještaje</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Dissenyadors visuals complets per a taules, consultes, formularis i informes</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Dissenyadors visuals complets per a taules, consultes, formularis i informes</li>
      <li xml:lang="de">Vollständiger visuelle Entwurf für Tabellen, Abfragen, Formulare und Berichte</li>
      <li xml:lang="el">Πλήρης οπτική σχεδίαση για πίνακες, ερωτήσεις, φόρμες και αναφορές</li>
      <li xml:lang="en-GB">Full visual designers for tables, queries, forms and reports</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">Herramientas de diseño completamente visuales para las tablas, consultas, formularios e informes.</li>
      <li xml:lang="et">Tabelite, päringute, vormide ja aruannete täielikult visuaalne kujundamine</li>
      <li xml:lang="fi">Täysin visuaalinen taulukoiden, kyselyjen, lomakkeiden ja raporttien suunnittelu</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">Conception complètement visuelle pour les tables, requêtes, formulaires et rapports</li>
      <li xml:lang="gl">Deseñadores completamente visuais para táboas, consultas, formularios e informes.</li>
      <li xml:lang="ia">Plen designator visual per tabelas, queries, formularios e reportos</li>
      <li xml:lang="id">Pendesain visual lengkap untuk tabel, queri, formulir, dan laporan</li>
      <li xml:lang="it">Progettazione completamente visuale di tabelle, query e report</li>
      <li xml:lang="ja">テーブル、クエリー、フォームおよびレポートをすべて視覚的にでデザインできます</li>
      <li xml:lang="ko">테이블, 질의, 양식 및 보고서를 편집하는 전체 비주얼 디자이너</li>
      <li xml:lang="nb">Fullstendig visuell utforming for tabeller, spøøringer, skjemaer og rapporter</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Volledige visueel ontwerpen van tabellen, zoekopdrachten, formulieren en rapporten</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">W pełni wizualna możliwość tworzenia tabel, zapytań, formularzy i raportów</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Desenhadores visuais completos para tabelas, pesquisas, formulários e relatórios</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Desenhos visuais completos para tabelas, pesquisas, formulários e relatórios</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Plne vizuálny návrh pre tabuľky, dotazy, formuláre a správy</li>
      <li xml:lang="sl">Popolni vizualni oblikovalci za tabele, poizvedbe, obrazce in poročila</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Fullständigt visuell konstruktion av tabeller, frågor, formulär och rapporter</li>
      <li xml:lang="tr">Tablolar, sorgular, formlar ve raporlar için tümüyle görsel tasarımcılar</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Повноцінне візуальне середовище для створення таблиць, запитів, форм та звітів.</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxFull visual designers for tables, queries, forms and reportsxx</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh-CN">数据表、查询、表单和报告的完整可视化设计器</li>
      <li>Running queries, support for parametrized queries</li>
      <li xml:lang="bs">Potrebno upite , podršku za parametrizovan upite</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Execució de consultes, admet consultes paramètriques</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Execució de consultes, admet consultes paramètriques</li>
      <li xml:lang="de">Ausführung von Abfragen, Unterstützung für parametrisierte Abfragen</li>
      <li xml:lang="el">Εκτέλεση ερωτήσεων, υποστήριξη για παραμετροποιηνένες ερωτήσεις</li>
      <li xml:lang="en-GB">Running queries, support for parametrised queries</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">Ejecución de consultas, soporte de consultas parametrizadas</li>
      <li xml:lang="et">Päringute sooritamine, parameetritega päringute toetamine</li>
      <li xml:lang="fi">Kyselyjen suoritus ja parametroitavien kyselyjen tuki</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">Exécution de requêtes, prise en charge des requêtes paramétrées</li>
      <li xml:lang="gl">Execución de consultas, e funcionalidade de consultas parametrizadas.</li>
      <li xml:lang="ia">Executar queries, supporto per queries parametrizate</li>
      <li xml:lang="id">Menjalankan queri, mendukung queri terparameterisasi</li>
      <li xml:lang="it">Esecuzione di query, supporto per le query parametriche</li>
      <li xml:lang="ja">クエリーの実行、パラメータ化クエリーのサポート</li>
      <li xml:lang="ko">질의 실행, 매개 변수화된 질의 지원</li>
      <li xml:lang="nb">Kjøre spørriner, støtte for parametriserte spørringer</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Zoekopdrachten uitvoeren, ondersteuning voor zoekopdrachten met parameters</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">Wykonywanie zapytań, obsługa dla zapytań parametrycznych</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Execução de pesquisas, suporte para pesquisas parametrizadas</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Execução de pesquisas, suporte para pesquisas parametrizadas</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Spúšťanie dotazov, podpora pre parametrizované dotazy</li>
      <li xml:lang="sl">Zagon poizvedb, podpora za parametrizirane poizvedbe</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Ställa frågor, stöd för parameterbaserade frågor</li>
      <li xml:lang="tr">Sorgu çalıştırma, parametreleştirilmiş sorgular</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Виконання запитів, підтримка параметризованих запитів.</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxRunning queries, support for parametrized queriesxx</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh-CN">执行查询，支持参数化查询</li>
      <li>Supports SQLite, MySQL, PostgreSQL, xBase, and Sybase/MS SQL Server databases</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Permet bases de dades SQLite, MySQL, PostgreSQL, xBase i Sybase/MS SQL Server</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Permet bases de dades SQLite, MySQL, PostgreSQL, xBase i Sybase/MS SQL Server</li>
      <li xml:lang="de">Unterstützt Datenbanken wie SQLite, MySQL, PostgreSQL, xBase und Sybase/MS SQL Server</li>
      <li xml:lang="el">Υποστηρίζει βάσεις δεδομένων SQLite, MySQL, PostgreSQL, xBase, και Sybase/MS SQL Server</li>
      <li xml:lang="en-GB">Supports SQLite, MySQL, PostgreSQL, xBase, and Sybase/MS SQL Server databases</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">Permite usar servidores de bases de datos SQLite, MySQL, PostgreSQL, xBase y Sybase/MS SQL</li>
      <li xml:lang="et">SQLite'i, MySQL'i, PostgreSQL-i, xBase'i ja Sybase/MS SQL Serveri andmebaaside toetamine</li>
      <li xml:lang="fi">SQLite-, MySQL-, PostgreSQL-, xBase- ja Sybase/MS SQL Server -tietokantojen tuki</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">Prend en charge les bases de données SQLite, MySQL, PostgreSQL, xBase et Sybase/MS SQL Server</li>
      <li xml:lang="gl">Compatíbel con bases de datos SQLite, MySQL, PostgreSQL, xBase, Sybase SQL Server e MS SQL Server.</li>
      <li xml:lang="ia">Supporta base de datos SQLite, MySQL, PostgreSQL, xBase, e Sybase/MS SQL Server</li>
      <li xml:lang="id">Dukungan database SQLite, MySQL, PostgreSQL, xBase, dan Sybase/MS SQL Server</li>
      <li xml:lang="it">Supporta SQLite, MySQL, PostgreSQL, xBase e banche dati Sybase/MS SQL Server</li>
      <li xml:lang="ko">SQLite, MySQL, PostgreSQL, xBase 및 Sybase/MS SQL Server 데이터베이스 지원</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Ondersteunt databases SQLite, MySQL, PostgreSQL, xBase en Sybase/MS SQL Server</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">Obsługa SQLite, MySQL, PostgreSQL, xBase oraz baz danych Sybase/MS SQL Server</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Suporta bases de dados SQLite, MySQL, PostgreSQL, xBase e Sybase/MS SQL Server</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Suporte aos banco de dados SQLite, MySQL, PostgreSQL, xBase e Sybase/MS SQL Server</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Podporuje serverové databázy SQLite, MySQL, PostgreSQL, xBase a Sybase/MS SQL</li>
      <li xml:lang="sl">Podpira baze podatkov SQLite, MySQL, PostgreSQL, xBase in Sybase/MS SQL Server</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Stöder databaserna SQLite, MySQL, PostgreSQL, xBase och Sybase/MS SQL Server</li>
      <li xml:lang="tr">SQLite, MySQL, PostgreSQL, xBase ve Sybase/MS SQL sunucusuu veritabanlarını destekler</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Підтримка баз даних SQLite, MySQL, PostgreSQL, xBase та Sybase/MS SQL.</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxSupports SQLite, MySQL, PostgreSQL, xBase, and Sybase/MS SQL Server databasesxx</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh-CN">支持 SQLite、MySQL、PostgreSQL、xBase 和 Sybase/MS SQL Server 等数据库</li>
      <li>The only multiplatform visual tool that can easily import data from MS Access databases</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">L'única eina visual multiplataforma que pot importar fàcilment dades des de les bases de dades MS Access</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">L'única eina visual multiplataforma que pot importar amb facilitat dades des de les bases de dades MS Access</li>
      <li xml:lang="de">Das einzige Programm mit grafischer Oberfläche für mehrere Plattformen, das Daten aus MS-Access-Datenbanken importieren kann.</li>
      <li xml:lang="el">Το μόνο οπτικό εργαλείο για πολλές πλατφόρμες που μπορεί εύκολα να εισάγει δεδομένα από βάσεις δεδομένων MS Access</li>
      <li xml:lang="en-GB">The only multiplatform visual tool that can easily import data from MS Access databases</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">La única herramienta gráfica multiplataforma que puede importar con facilidad datos de las bases de datos de MS Access</li>
      <li xml:lang="et">Ainuke mitmel platvormil töötav visuaalne töörist MS Accessi andmebaaside andmete importimiseks</li>
      <li xml:lang="fi">Ainoa useampialustainen visuaalinen työkalu, jolla voi helposti tuoda tietoja MS Access -tietokannoista</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">Le seul outil visuel multi plates-formes qui importe les bases de données de MS Access</li>
      <li xml:lang="gl">A única ferramenta visual multiplataforma que pode importar facilmente datos de bases de datos de MS Access.</li>
      <li xml:lang="ia">Le sol instrumento visual multiplatteforma que pote importar facilemente datos ex base de datos de MS Access</li>
      <li xml:lang="id">Satu-satunya alat visual multiplatform yang dapat dengan mudah mengimpor data dari database MS Access</li>
      <li xml:lang="it">Il solo strumento grafico multipiattaforma in grado di importare facilmente da banche dati MS Access</li>
      <li xml:lang="ko">MS Access 데이터베이스에서 데이터를 쉽게 가져올 수 있는 유일한 멀티플랫폼 비주얼 도구</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Het enige multiplatform visuele hulpmiddel die gemakkelijk gegevens kan importeren uit MS Access databases</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">Jedyne graficzne narzędzie wieloplatformowe, dzięki któremu łatwo można zaimportować dane z baz danych MS Access</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">A única ferramenta gráfica multi-plataforma que consegue importar facilmente bases de dados MS Access</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Única ferramenta visual e multiplataforma que consegue importar facilmente um banco de dados do MS Access</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Jediný mnohoplatformový grafický nástroj importujúci údaje z databáz MS Access</li>
      <li xml:lang="sl">Edino vizualno orodje na več platformah, ki zlahka uvaža podatke iz baze podatkov MS Access</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Det enda visuella verktyget för flera plattformar som enkelt kan importera data från MS Access-databaser</li>
      <li xml:lang="tr">MS Access veritabanlarından veri içe aktarabilen tek çoklu platformlu görsel araç</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Єдиний візуальний багатоплатформовий інструмент, здатний без проблем імпортувати дані з баз даних MS Access.</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxThe only multiplatform visual tool that can easily import data from MS Access databasesxx</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh-CN">唯一一款可以轻松导入 MS Access 数据库数据的跨平台可视化工具</li>
      <li>Support for query design in dedicated SQL view</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Permet el disseny de consultes en vistes SQL dedicades</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Permet el disseny de consultes en vistes SQL dedicades</li>
      <li xml:lang="de">Unterstützt Abfrageentwürfe in einer eigenen SQL-Ansicht</li>
      <li xml:lang="el">Υποστήριξη για σχεδίαση ερωτήσεων σε αφιερωμένη προβολή SQL</li>
      <li xml:lang="en-GB">Support for query design in dedicated SQL view</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">Permite el diseño de consultas en vista SQL dedicada</li>
      <li xml:lang="et">Päringute kujundamise toetamine SQL-vaates</li>
      <li xml:lang="fi">Kyselyn suunnittelun tuki SQL-näkymässä</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">Prend en charge la conception de requêtes SQL dans une vue dédiée</li>
      <li xml:lang="gl">Funcionalidade de deseño de consultas nunha vista de SQL dedicada.</li>
      <li xml:lang="ia">Supporto per designo de query in vista de SQL dedicate</li>
      <li xml:lang="id">Dukungan untuk desain queri dalam tampilan SQL terdedikasi</li>
      <li xml:lang="it">Supporta la progettazione di query in una vista SQL dedicata</li>
      <li xml:lang="ko">전용 SQL 보기에서 질의 디자인 지원</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Ondersteuning voor ontwerp van zoekopdrachten in een gerichte SQL-weergave</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">Obsługa tworzenia zapytań w widoku przeznaczonym dla SQL</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Suporta o desenho de pesquisas numa área de SQL dedicada</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Suporte para desenho de pesquisas em uma área de SQL dedicada</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Podporuje návrh dotazov vo vyhradenom SQL pohľade</li>
      <li xml:lang="sl">Podpora za oblikovanje poizvedb v namenskem pogledu SQL</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Stöd för frågekonstruktion i en dedicerad SQL-vy</li>
      <li xml:lang="tr">Özel SQL görünümünde sorgu tasarımı desteği</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Підтримка створення запитів за допомогою спеціальної панелі SQL.</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxSupport for query design in dedicated SQL viewxx</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh-CN">支持专用 SQL 视图中的查询设计</li>
      <li>Designing and displaying relational data using combo boxes (lookup columns)</li>
      <li xml:lang="bs">Izrada i prikazivanje relacijskih podataka pomoću combo kutije ( pregledavanje kolone)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Disseny i visualització de dades relacionals usant quadres combinats (columnes de cerca)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Disseny i visualització de dades relacionals utilitzant quadros combinats (columnes de busca)</li>
      <li xml:lang="de">Entwurf und Anzeige von relationalen Daten mit Hilfe von Kombinationsfeldern (Nachschlagspalten)</li>
      <li xml:lang="el">Σχεδιασμός και εμφάνιση σχεσιακών δεδομένων με χρήση συνδυαστικών πλαισίων (στήλες αναζήτησης)</li>
      <li xml:lang="en-GB">Designing and displaying relational data using combo boxes (lookup columns)</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">Diseño y presentación de datos relacionales utilizando listas desplegables (columnas de búsqueda)</li>
      <li xml:lang="et">Relatsiooniliste andmete kujundamine ja kuvamine liitkastide abil (päringuveerud)</li>
      <li xml:lang="fi">Relaatiotiedon suunnittelu ja näyttö yhdistelmäkenttiä käyttäen (hakusarakkeet)</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">Conception et affichage des données relationnelles à l'aide de listes déroulantes (colonnes de consultation)</li>
      <li xml:lang="gl">Deseño e mostra de datos relacionais mediante caixas despregábeis (columnas de busca).</li>
      <li xml:lang="ia">Designante e monstrante datos relational per usar  listas combinate (columnas de cerca)</li>
      <li xml:lang="id">Pendesainan dan pendisplaian data yang berhubungan menggunakan kotak kombo (kolom-kolom dangak)</li>
      <li xml:lang="it">Progettazione e visualizzazione dei dati relazionali utilizzando caselle combinate (colonne di ricerca)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ja">コンボボックスを使用した関係データのデザインと表示(参照列)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ko">콤보 상자를 사용하여 관계형 데이터 디자인 및 표시(조회 열)</li>
      <li xml:lang="nb">Utforming og visning av relasjonsdata vhja kombo-bokser (oppslagskolonner)</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Ontwerpen en tonen van relationele gegevens met gebruik van keuzelijsten (kolommen voor opzoeken)</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">Opracowywanie i wyświetlanie danych relacyjnych przy użyciu pól rozwijanych (kolumn wyszukiwania)</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Desenho e apresentação de dados relacionais com listas (colunas de pesquisa)</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Desenho e apresentação de dados relacionais usando listas (colunas de pesquisa)</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Návrh a zobrazenie relačných dát pomocou combo boxov (lookup stĺpce)</li>
      <li xml:lang="sl">Oblikovanje in prikaz relacijskih podatkov s pomočjo kombiniranih polj (stolpcev za iskanje)</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Konstruktion och visning av relationsdata med användning av kombinationsrutor (uppslagning av kolumner)</li>
      <li xml:lang="tr">Çoklu kutular kullanarak (sütun arama) ilişkisel veri tasarlama ve görüntüleme</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Створення та показ пов’язаних даних за допомогою спадних списків (стовпчики пошуку).</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxDesigning and displaying relational data using combo boxes (lookup columns)xx</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh-CN">使用下拉选单设计和显示关系数据 (查找列)</li>
      <li>Direct data entry or import using CSV format</li>
      <li xml:lang="bs">Unos podataka direktno  ili uvoz pomoću CSV formata</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Entrada directa de dades o importació usant el format CSV</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Entrada directa de dades o importació utilitzant el format CSV</li>
      <li xml:lang="de">Direkte Dateneingabe oder Import aus dem CSV-Format</li>
      <li xml:lang="el">Άμεση εγγραφή δεδομένων ή εισαγωγή με χρήση τύπου αποθήκευσης CSV</li>
      <li xml:lang="en-GB">Direct data entry or import using CSV format</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">Entrada directa de datos o importación utilizando el formato CSV</li>
      <li xml:lang="et">Otsene andmete sisestamine või importimine CSV-vormingus</li>
      <li xml:lang="fi">Suora tiedon syöttö tai tuonti CSV-muodossa</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">Saisie directe de données ou import utilisant le format CSV</li>
      <li xml:lang="gl">Introdución directa de datos ou importación en formato CSV.</li>
      <li xml:lang="ia">Entrata de datos directe o importation usante formato CSV</li>
      <li xml:lang="id">Entri data langsung atau impor menggunakan format CSV</li>
      <li xml:lang="it">Inserimento diretto dei dati o importazione utilizzando il formato CSV</li>
      <li xml:lang="ja">CSV を使用したダイレクトデータの入力もしくはインポート</li>
      <li xml:lang="ko">CSV 형식을 사용하여 직접 데이터 입력 또는 가져오기</li>
      <li xml:lang="nb">Direkte datainnskriving eller import med CSV-format</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Directe invoer van gegevens of importeren met het CSV-format</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">Bezpośrednie wprowadzanie danych lub importowanie ich z postaci CSV</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Introdução ou importação directa de dados com o formato CSV</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Entrada ou importação direta de dados usando o formato CSV</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Priamy vstup údajov alebo import pomocou formátu CSV</li>
      <li xml:lang="sl">Neposreden vnos ali uvoz podatkov v formatu CSV</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Direkt datainmatning eller import med CSV-format</li>
      <li xml:lang="tr">Doğrudan veri girişi veya CSV biçimi ile içe aktarma</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Безпосереднє введення даних або імпортування даних у форматі CSV.</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxDirect data entry or import using CSV formatxx</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh-CN">使用 CSV 格式直接输入或导入数据</li>
      <li>Locked down User Mode, allowing you to switch off all commands related to editing your project's design</li>
      <li xml:lang="bs">Zatvoreni  korisnički režim, omogućavajući vam da isključite sve naredbe koje se odnose na uređivanje dizajna vašeg projekta</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Mode reduït d'usuari, que permet inhabilitar totes les ordres relacionades amb l'edició del disseny del projecte</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Mode reduït d'usuari, que permet inhabilitar totes les ordres relacionades amb l'edició del disseny del projecte</li>
      <li xml:lang="de">Gesperrter Benutzermodus, der es Ihnen ermöglicht, alle Befehle für die Bearbeitung des Entwurfs Ihres Projekts auszuschalten.</li>
      <li xml:lang="el">Κλειδωμένη λειτουργία χρήστη, που σας επιτρέπει να απενεργοποιήσετε όλες τις εντολές που σχετίζονται με την επεξεργασία της σχεδίασης του έργου σας</li>
      <li xml:lang="en-GB">Locked down User Mode, allowing you to switch off all commands related to editing your project's design</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">Modo de usuario limitado, que permite desactivar todas las ordenes relacionadas con la edición del diseño de su proyecto</li>
      <li xml:lang="et">Piiratud õigustega kasutajarežiim, mis võimaldab lülitada välja kõik projekti kujunduse muutmisega seotud käsud</li>
      <li xml:lang="fi">Lukittu käyttäjätila, jossa voit poistaa käytöstä projektin suunnitteluun liittyvät komennot</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">Mode utilisateur verrouillé, vous permettant de désactiver toutes les commandes liées à la modification de la conception de votre projet</li>
      <li xml:lang="gl">Modo de usuario bloqueado, que permite desactivar todas as ordes de edición do deseño do proxecto.</li>
      <li xml:lang="ia">Modo de usator confinate, que te permitte commutar omne commandos referite al modificar tu designo de projecto</li>
      <li xml:lang="id">Mode User terkunci, memungkinkan Anda untuk mematikankan semua perintah yang berhubungan untuk pengeditan desain projek Anda</li>
      <li xml:lang="it">Modalità utente bloccata, che ti consente di disattivare tutti i comandi in grado di modificare la struttura del tuo progetto.</li>
      <li xml:lang="ja">プロジェクトデザインの編集スイッチをオフにする事でユーザモードへのロックダウンが可能</li>
      <li xml:lang="ko">잠긴 사용자 모드를 사용하여 프로젝트 디자인 편집과 관련된 모든 명령을 끌 수 있습니다</li>
      <li xml:lang="nb">Låst brukermodus, slik at du kan slå av alle kommandoer som gjelder endring av prosjektets utforming</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Vergrendelde gebruikersodus, waarmee u alle commando's uitschakelt die zijn gerelateerd aan bewerken en ontwerpen van uw project</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">Zamknięty tryb użytkownika, umożliwiający wyłączenie wszystkich poleceń związanych z edytowaniem twojego projektu</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Modo reduzido de utilizador, permitindo-lhe desligar todos os comandos relacionados com a edição do desenho do seu projecto</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Modo de usuário reduzido, permitindo-lhe desligar todos os comandos relacionados à edição do visual do seu projeto</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Uzamknutý používateľský režim, umožňujúci vám vypnúť všetky príkazy súvisiace s úpravou dizajnu vášho projektu</li>
      <li xml:lang="sl">Zaklenjen uporabniški način, vam omogoča izklop vseh ukazov v zvezi urejanja zasnove vašega projekta</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Låsbart användarläge, som låter dig stänga av alla kommandon relaterade till redigering av projektets konstruktion</li>
      <li xml:lang="tr">Projenizin tasarımını değiştirmeyi kapatan, sınırlandırılmış Kullanıcı Kipi</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Заблокований режим користувача, у якому можна вимкнути усі пов’язані з командами редагування компонування вашого проєкту команди.</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxLocked down User Mode, allowing you to switch off all commands related to editing your project's designxx</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh-CN">锁定用户模式，可以关闭所有与编辑项目设计相关的命令</li>
      <li>Scripting using JavaScript, Python or Ruby programming languages (experimental)</li>
      <li xml:lang="bs">Scripting koristeći JavaScript, Python ili Ruby programskim jezicima (eksperimentalno)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca">Crear scripts usant els llenguatges de programació JavaScript, Python o Ruby (experimental)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ca-valencia">Crear scripts utilitzant els llenguatges de programació JavaScript, Python o Ruby (experimental)</li>
      <li xml:lang="de">Unterstützung für Skripte in den Programmsprachen JavaScript, Python oder Ruby (experimentell)</li>
      <li xml:lang="el">Συγγραφή σεναρίων με τη χρήση γλωσσών JavaScript, Python ή Ruby (πειραματικό)</li>
      <li xml:lang="en-GB">Scripting using JavaScript, Python or Ruby programming languages (experimental)</li>
      <li xml:lang="es">Programación de scripts escritos en los lenguajes de programación JavaScript, Python o Ruby (experimental)</li>
      <li xml:lang="et">Skriptimisvõimalused JavaScripti, Pythoni või Ruby programmeerimiskeeles (eksperimentaalne)</li>
      <li xml:lang="fi">Skriptaus JavaScript-, Python- tai Ruby-ohjelmointikielillä (kokeellinen)</li>
      <li xml:lang="fr">Pilotage par scripts utilisant les langages de programmation JavaScript, Python ou Ruby (expérimental)</li>
      <li xml:lang="gl">Uso de scripts nas linguaxes de programación JavaScript, Python e Ruby (experimental).</li>
      <li xml:lang="ia">Scripting usante linguages de programmation JavaScript, Python o Ruby (experimental)</li>
      <li xml:lang="id">Penskripan menggunakan bahasa pemrograman JavaScript, Python atau Ruby</li>
      <li xml:lang="it">Creazione script utilizzando i linguaggi di programmazione JavaScript, Python o Ruby (sperimentale)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ja">JavaScript, Python や Ruby を使用してのスクリプティング(実験的)</li>
      <li xml:lang="ko">자바스크립트, Python 또는 루비 프로그래밍 언어를 사용한 스크립팅(실험적)</li>
      <li xml:lang="nb">Skripting ved bruk av JavaScript, Python eller Ruby programmeringsspråk (eksperimentelt)</li>
      <li xml:lang="nl">Scripting met de programmeertalen JavaScript, Python of Ruby (experimenteel)</li>
      <li xml:lang="pl">Skrypty wykorzystujące języki programowania JavaScript, Python lub Ruby (eksperymentalnie)</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt">Programável através das linguagens JavaScript, Python ou Ruby (experimental)</li>
      <li xml:lang="pt-BR">Criação de scripts usando as linguagens de programação JavaScript, Python ou Ruby (experimental)</li>
      <li xml:lang="sk">Skriptovanie pomocou programovacích jazykov JavaScript, Python alebo Ruby (experimentálne)</li>
      <li xml:lang="sl">Raba skriptov v programskih jezikih JavaScript, Python ali Ruby (poskusno)</li>
      <li xml:lang="sv">Skript med användning av programspråken Javascript, Python eller Ruby (experimentellt)</li>
      <li xml:lang="tr">JavaScript, Python veya Ruby programlama dillerini kullanarak betik yazımı desteği (deneysel)</li>
      <li xml:lang="uk">Керування за допомогою скриптів мовами JavaScript, Python та Ruby (експериментальна можливість).</li>
      <li xml:lang="x-test">xxScripting using JavaScript, Python or Ruby programming languages (experimental)xx</li>
      <li xml:lang="zh-CN">使用 JavaScript、Python 或 Ruby 编程语言编写脚本 (实验性)</li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  <url type="homepage">http://www.kexi-project.org</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://bugs.kde.org/enter_bug.cgi?product=kexi</url>
  <url type="help">https://userbase.kde.org/Kexi/Handbook</url>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>http://kexi-project.org/pics/3.0/kexi-3.0.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Tabular view</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca">Vista de taules</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca-valencia">Vista de taules</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="de">Tabellarische Ansicht</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="el">Προβολή σε στήλες</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="en-GB">Tabular view</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="es">Vista tabular</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="et">Tabelivaade</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fi">Taulukkonäkymä</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fr">Vue tabulaire</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="gl">Vista de táboa</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ia">Vista a tabellas</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="id">Tampilan tabular</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="it">Vista tabellare</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ka">ჩანართებიანი ხედი</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ko">표 형식 보기</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nl">Tabelweergave</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pl">Widok tabeli</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt">Vista em tabelas</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt-BR">Exibição em tabelas</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sk">Tabuľkový pohľad</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sl">Tabelni pogled</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sv">Tabellvy</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="tr">Sekmeli görünüm</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="uk">Перегляд таблиць</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="x-test">xxTabular viewxx</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="zh-CN">数据表视图</caption>
      <image>http://kexi-project.org/pics/3.0/kexi-3.0-table-view.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Query Designer</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca">Dissenyador de consultes</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca-valencia">Dissenyador de consultes</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="cs">Návrhář dotazů</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="de">Abfrage-Designer</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="el">Πρόγραμμα σχεδίασης ερωτήσεων</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="en-GB">Query Designer</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="es">Diseñador de consultas</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="et">Päringukujundaja</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fi">Kyselyjen suunnittelu</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fr">Concepteur de requêtes</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="gl">Deseñador de consultas</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ia">Designator de Query</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="id">Pendesain Queri</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="it">Strumento di progettazione delle query</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ka">მოთხოვნის დიზაინერ</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ko">질의 디자이너</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nl">Ontwerper van query</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pl">Opracowywanie zapytań</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt">Desenhador de Pesquisas</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt-BR">Designer de pesquisas</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sk">Návrhár dotazov</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sl">Oblikovalnik poizvedb</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sv">Frågekonstruktion</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="tr">Sorgu Tasarımcısı</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="uk">Засіб для розробки запитів</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="x-test">xxQuery Designerxx</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="zh-CN">查询设计器</caption>
      <image>http://kexi-project.org/pics/3.1/kexi-3.1-query-designer.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>SQL Editor</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca">Editor de SQL</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca-valencia">Editor de SQL</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="cs">Editor SQL</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="de">SQL-Editor</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="el">επεξεργαστής SQL</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="en-GB">SQL Editor</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="es">Editor SQL</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="et">SQL-redaktor</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fi">SQL-muokkain</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fr">Éditeur SQL</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="gl">Editor de SQL</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ia">Editor SQL</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="id">Pengedit SQL</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="it">Editor SQL</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ka">SQL რედაქტორი</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ko">SQL 편집기</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nl">SQL-bewerker</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pl">Edytor SQL</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt">Editor de SQL</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt-BR">Editor SQL</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sk">SQL editor</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sl">Urejevalnik SQL</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sv">SQL-editor</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="tr">SQL Düzenleyicisi</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="uk">Редактор SQL</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="x-test">xxSQL Editorxx</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="zh-CN">SQL 编辑器</caption>
      <image>http://kexi-project.org/pics/3.0/kexi-3.0-alpha-sql_editor.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Form Designer</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="bs">Obrazac Designer</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca">Dissenyador de formularis</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca-valencia">Dissenyador de formularis</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="cs">Návrhář formulářů</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="de">Formular-Designer</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="el">Πρόγραμμα σχεδίασης φορμών</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="en-GB">Form Designer</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="es">Diseñador de formularios</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="et">Vormikujundaja</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fi">Lomakkeiden suunnittelu</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fr">Concepteur de formulaires</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="gl">Deseñador de formularios</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ia">Designator de formato</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="id">Pendesain Formulir</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="it">Progettazione moduli</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ja">フォームデザイナー</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ka">ფორმის დიზაინერი</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ko">양식 디자이너</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nb">Skjemautformer</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nl">Ontwerper van formulieren</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pl">Opracowywanie formularzy</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt">Desenhador de Formulários</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt-BR">Ferramenta de desenho de formulários</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sk">Návrhár formulárov</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sl">Oblikovalnik obrazcev</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sv">Formulärkonstruktion</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="tr">Form Tasarımcısı</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="uk">Засіб для розробки форм.</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="x-test">xxForm Designerxx</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="zh-CN">表单设计器</caption>
      <image>http://kexi-project.org/pics/3.0/kexi-3.0-compare-old.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Report Designer</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca">Dissenyador d'informes</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca-valencia">Dissenyador d'informes</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="cs">Návrhář hlášení</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="de">Berichts-Designer</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="el">Πρόγραμμα σχεδίασης αναφορών</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="en-GB">Report Designer</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="es">Diseñador de informes</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="et">Aruandekujundaja</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fi">Raporttien suunnittelu</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fr">Concepteur de rapports</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="gl">Deseñador de informes</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ia">Designator de Reporto</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="id">Pendesain Laporan</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="it">Strumento di progettazione di report</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ka">ანგარიშის დიზაინერი</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ko">보고서 디자이너</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nl">Ontwerper van rapporten</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pl">Opracowywanie sprawozdań</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt">Desenhador de Formulários</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt-BR">Ferramenta de desenho de relatórios</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sk">Návrhár reportov</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sl">Oblikovalnik poročil</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sv">Rapportkonstruktion</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="tr">Rapor Tasarımcı</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="uk">Засіб для розробки звітів</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="x-test">xxReport Designerxx</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="zh-CN">报表设计器</caption>
      <image>http://kexi-project.org/pics/3.1/kreport-3.1-custompagesize.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>MS Access database import</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca">Importació d'una base de dades de MS Access</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ca-valencia">Importació d'una base de dades de MS Access</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="cs">Import databáze MS Access</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="de">Import von MS Access Datenbank</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="el">Εισαγωγή βάσης δεδομένων MS Access</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="en-GB">MS Access database import</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="es">Importación de bases de datos de MS Access</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="et">MS Accessi andmebaasi import</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fi">MS Access -tietokannan tuonti</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="fr">Importation de base de données MS Access</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="gl">Importación da base de datos de MS Access</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ia">Importation de base de datos MS Access</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="id">Impor database MS Access</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="it">Importazione banca dati MS Access</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ka">ბაზის შემოტანა MS Access-დან</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="ko">MS Access 데이터베이스 가져오기</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="nl">Importeren van MS Access database</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pl">Importowanie bazy danych MS Access</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt">Importação de bases de dados MS Access</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="pt-BR">Importação de bancos de dados MS Access</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sk">Import databázy MS Access</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sl">Uvoz podatkov iz podatkovne baze MS Access</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="sv">MS Access-databasimport</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="tr">MS Access veritabanı içe aktarma</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="uk">Імпортування баз даних MS Access</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="x-test">xxMS Access database importxx</caption>
      <caption xml:lang="zh-CN">MS Access 数据库导入</caption>
      <image>http://kexi-project.org/pics/3.1/kexi-3.1-import-ms-access.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <project_group>KDE</project_group>
  <provides>
    <binary>kexi-3.2</binary>
  </provides>
</component>
